ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
木浅薰
showeryhe
翻译
煮粥达人
电脑团
翻译
静妹粒  累
冬麟  ET外星人
时间轴
大葱ALX  兜兜兜爹  念念
电脑狂人
第三季
第二集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
在我们的网站上  用户已经可以交谈
On our network, users can already have a conversation,
收发电邮  分享信息  交朋友
send mail, share information, connect.
但我们将迈出更大的一步
But this promises to be far more.
这将是世界上首次实现虚拟握手成交
This is the world's first virtual handshake deal.
-一次交易  -这种交易通过电脑完成
- A trade. - A trade made on your computer
让用户可以交换实体物品
that swaps tangible items between users.
不用出门  一切触手可得
You get everything you want without ever leaving your home.
敲击键盘即可完成
You do everything from your keyboard.
唯一需要你打交道的就是快递员
The only person you'll ever see is the mailman.
我们需要一个合适的合作伙伴
We're looking for the right partner.
我们的忠实用户已达十万  而且还在增加
We've currently got 100,000 dedicated users and we're growing,
所以这种规模的扩张需要更大规模的注资
so expansion like this requires another level of funding.
我们需要向程序团队补充更多人手
We need to add more bodies to the coding team,
-强化用户界面并购进...  -多少钱
- enhance our interface, and purchase... - How much?
在我们的计划书最后
In the back of our prospectus
有详细的分析...
you'll find a detailed breakdown of...
我看到了  我只想听你们大声说出来
I saw the number. I'd just like to hear it said out loud.
140万
$1.4 million.
我们的用户群很忠实
Our base is loyal
且取得成功后成本才会增加
and costs only rise in success.
所以我们的客户流失率  见第25页
So our churn rate, page 25,
和消耗率  见第26页
and our burn rate, 26,
都低到基本可以忽略
are practically nonexistent.
光是第一年  我们相信穆特尼易物
In its first year alone, we believe Mutiny Exchange
交易量将会超过50万笔
will see upwards of a half a million deals.
今天我们想把这笔开门交易给您来做
Today, we're offering you the opportunity to make the first one.
没说错吧  麦克
Told you, Mac.
还真是  果然是一流
You were right. First-rate.
近一段时间以来最精彩的了
best I've heard in a while.
为什么拖到这么晚才来找我
Why am I one of the last to hear it?
因为我们在分析风投市场的行情
Because we've been assessing the vc landscape...
我听说你们拿着这个找了好几家风投了
I've heard you've been up and down Sand Hill Road with this.
我们是新手  急需投资
Well, we're new in town. We're hungry
所以急于寻找合伙人
and we want to move fast.
我理解
Okay, I get that.
86年第二季度我们一共投了27家公司
Our portfolio is 27 companies deep as of q2 '86.
我们投资了3com和思科  还有
We are in on 3com and Cisco and...
糟了  蒂姆  我想起来了
Shit, Tim, that reminds me,
我还得给桑蒂[思科创始人]回电话
I gotta call Sandy back.
你投资回报最好的是甲骨文
One of your best was Oracle.
上个月首募200万股  每股55块
Ipo'd last month, two million shares, $55 a pop.
确实  拉里让我们赚了5500万
Sure did. Larry made us $55 million.
你是说你也能做到吗
Are you telling me you could do the same?
从5500万里借140万给我  赚给你看
Well, lend us 1.4 of that 55 and we'll show you.
我们过去吃过亏
We've been burned in the past.
我们入场出手
We will throw our hat in the ring
报价却被人满世界宣扬
only to have our offer shot up and down the valley.
我不喜欢玩虚的
I don't like games
更不喜欢被人当成抬价的筹码
and I don't want to be used as a stalking horse.
如果我们同意投资  跟你们签了风投协议
If we were to move on this and give you a term sheet,
你们就不能再找别家
we'd want a no-shop in return.
不想做生意我们也不会来了
We wouldn't be here if we weren't ready to do business.
打扰一下  麦克米伦先生
Excuse me, Mr. MacMillan, sir.
能占用你一点时间吗
If I can have a moment of your time.
先生
Sir.
三千分之一
3,000 to one.
这是一生中被雷电击中一次的几率
Those are the odds of getting hit by lightning in your lifetime.
也是被网络病毒攻击的几率
They're also the odds of getting hit by a computer virus.
但是只要五年左右  这几率就会大幅提高
But in, like, five years, those odds are gonna go way up.
我是说病毒  不是雷击
For... for viruses, not lightning.
所以你的工作才无比重要
But that's why your work is so critical.
因为人们都只盯着眼下
Because people are focused on today
你已经放眼未来了
and you're already into tomorrow.
-你有名字吗  -当然  我叫莱恩
- Do you have a name? - Yeah, of course. It's Ryan.
莱恩·雷
Ryan Ray.
莱恩  海水现在只有11度
Ryan, it's 52 degrees in that water.
等我换点干衣服的
I'm gonna get into some dry clothes.
我为穆特尼工作
I work for Mutiny
和卡梅伦·豪伊还有戈登·克拉克
with Cameron Howe and Gordon Clark.
麦克米伦实用网络就是稍加修饰的索纳里斯病毒
MacMillan Utility is basically sonaris virus with lipstick.
452千行代码中只有两千行不同
And only two klocs out of 452 separate it.
而这两千行代码完全改变了
And those two klocs completely changed
整个程序的作用和目的
the functionality and purpose of the entire program.
实在太厉害了
It's completely amazing.
而且  我用了不到一天就拆解出来了
And, you know, I pulled it apart in less than a day.
是想震撼我吗  莱恩
Trying to impress me, Ryan?
是的  差不多就是个目的
Uh, yeah, that was sort of the point.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
当然  随便问
Yeah, sure, anything.
海湾有13个点可以冲浪
The bay area has 13 breaks worth surfing.
找到我之前你去了几个
How many did you go to before you found me?
说实话吗  4个
Honestly? Four.
11个
11.
12天了  还是那个样
12 days and the same old song and dance.
他还在做麦克的工作
He's still working on Mac.
好吧  要么蒂姆在嘴炮  要么就没啥本事
Okay, so then Tim's either full of shit or he's got no juice.
哈珀是我们最后的希望
Harpor was our last shot.
我们还有一些会面
We've got a couple more meetings,
但都是些小公司
but they're smaller boutique firms.
要是我们第一轮筹款就到处被拒
If we get denied first-round funding across the board,
那不管我们接下来做什么
then it'll be impossible to get that stink off
都很难摆脱这个形象了
no matter what we do next.
我不明白  这个主意很棒
I don't get it. The idea is great.
每场面谈的计划书都很出彩
The prospectus kicks ass every meeting we've gone into.
14个风投公司没一个愿意接  为什么呢
14 VC firms and nobody's stepped up, why?
这些混蛋就爱晾着你
Well, these clowns love to make you wait.
他们觉得这让自己显得更有吸引力
They think it gives them some kind of an allure.
但只要有一个邀你去舞会就够了
But it just takes one of them to ask you to the dance.
老天爷  这一行打比方都这么性别歧视
God, I love how even the metaphors in this business are sexist.
我们可以拿出各种数据和事实
We can hit them with all the data and all the hard facts we want,
但我们一走进去  他们只能看到一件事
but the minute we walk in there, they still see just one thing.
你们别总想着是自己的原因嘛
You guys can't take this stuff so personally.
但我们就是这家公司
But this company is us.
别急嘛
Well, just give it time.
博斯  这几周没一个投资人联系我们
Bos, we haven't heard back from a single investor in weeks.
那你要我说什么
What do you want me to say?
你们俩是女人这一事实
Look, the fact that you two are women
确实不是什么加分项
I'm sure doesn't help matters.
我倒宁愿你继续骗我们
I think I liked it better when you were lying to us.
那些风投都是笑面虎
These smiling VCs out here
就喜欢笑嘻嘻地搞死你
love to grin and screw you, don't they?
德克萨斯起码还明刀明枪
At least in Texas they stab you in the front.
怎么了
What?
哈珀资本的蒂姆·汉克尔
Tim Hankel from Harpor Capital.
蒂姆  麦克回复你了吗
Tim, hey, have you heard from Mac yet
还是我该继续打电话
or do I have to keep calling you
直到你对我们下限制令
until you take out a restraining order on me?
我知道
Ha, I know, I know.
抱歉拖了那么久  但都是值得的
I'm sorry it's taking so long, but it was worth it.
说好了
We are a go.
我说了会拉麦克进来  我说到做到
I told you I'd get Mac on board and I'm a man of my word.
他刚从阿斯彭回来  但明天就飞洛杉矶
He just got back from Aspen, but he's off to LA tomorrow,
他希望走之前把事情都打点好
So he wants something in place before he leaves.
方便今晚聊聊初步计划吗
You two free to talk first steps tonight?
好  我们查查日程安排再回复
Yes, let me check my schedule and get back to you.
不用转向语句就可以
No, you can do that without the goto statements.
不必要的跳转能省则省
And it's always better without spaghetti branching.
结构化程序  伯姆-贾可皮尼定理
Structured programing. Bohm-Jacopini style.
伯姆-贾可皮尼  好嘞
Bohm-Jacopini. You got it.
嗯  我会写下来的
Yeah, I'll write it down.
闲庭信步  无所事事  西装革履
Walking the floor, not really working, wearing a tie.
你想进管理层吗
You looking to become management?
什么  非也
What? No, no.
我今天还有一场取证
I got another bullshit deposition today.
明天还得去
Going in tomorrow, too.
起诉麦克米伦的案子吗
MacMillan lawsuit?
没错
Yep.
这个月都三次了
That's three already this month.
是不是很可怕
Is that intimidating?
在乔·麦克米伦直瞪瞪的眼神下接受盘问
Getting grilled with Joe MacMillan staring at you with those eyes of his?
他不在现场  只有我和律师
No, he's not there. It's just me and the lawyers.
无聊多于残酷
More boring than brutal.
他们不断问你同一个愚蠢的问题
You know, they ask you the same stupid questions over and over,
指望你出错
hoping you'll slip up.
我就盼着快点了事
Give anything if it was to be over
好赶紧拿支票走人
so I can collect the damn check already.
那真不错  你最好先把领带上的玉米片弄掉
That'd be sweet. Better brush the nacho dust off your tie first.
好了  先生们
Okay, gentlemen.
先生们  又到每周例会时间了
Gentlemen, it's that time of the week again.
我懂  我也很高兴
I know. I love it, too.
好了  关于你们的供应需求  得说明白点
All right, I need some clarification on your supply needs.
因为上次有点误解
Because, well, there was a bit of confusion last time.
我们买入2400调制解调器后
After we made the deal with Hayes for the 2400s,
我收到了执行部的电话
I got on the phone with the fella from fulfillment
问我要不要那些附加的RS-232串口设备
and he asked if I wanted those additional RS-232 cables
受你们英明的指教  我回答说
to which I, per your wise instruction, reply,
"不  先生  那不是我要的那种机器人"
"No, sir, those are not the droids that I'm looking for."
于是他笑破肚皮之后
So after he got done laughing his ass off,
他解释说肯定有人在戏弄我
he explained that someone must be messing with me.
干得好  孩子们  我很感激
Well done, boys. I appreciate it.
继续
Moving on.
好了  我需要了解你们正在做的
All right, I need an update on the graphics extension
穆特尼易物演示系统的图形扩展的进度
for the Mutiny Exchange demo y'all are working on.
以及它将如何与周围已有的图形处理组件相连
And how it will interface with existing neighborhood graphics.
精灵引擎差不多弄好了
We have the sprite engine mostly working,
但是扫描线渲染还有点问题
but we still have a problem with the scan line rendering.
对  拼接地图缺失缓存
Yeah, we're getting a tile map cache miss,
所以调色板不同步
So we're losing synchronization on the palette.
好的  等等
Okay, well, hold it.
调色板连接的问题...
So is the thing with the palette connected to the...
就像我上次说的
As I said last time...
我们应该在位图上用位块传送器
...We should be using a blitter on a bitmap
这样才能在软件中来做
so we can do it in software
而不会让那些
and not freeze out devices
不支持硬件精灵的设备死机
that don't have support for hardware sprites.
好的  慢点  大家都同意吗
Okay, slow down. Slow down. Are we in agreement here?
你这是完全改变思路
You're talking about a whole new change of course.
没关系  把我们说的写下来就好
Doesn't matter. Just scribble down what we say,
交给卡梅伦  她能看懂
Give it to Cameron, she'll understand what we're talking about
别浪费我们的时间了
and stop wasting our time.
我不确定我都听懂了
You know, I'm not sure I got all that.
有时候我有点迟钝
See, sometimes I'm a bit slow.
需要别人跟我重复一遍
Need things repeated to me twice.
你干吗不站起来当面跟我说呢
Why don't you stand up and say that to my face?
你想站起来  对我重复一遍吗
You want to stand right up and repeat that to my face, son?
博斯  你有时间吗
Hey, Bos. Bos, you got a sec?
很快就好  博斯
Real quick. Bos.
听着  我知道你讨厌开这些会
Hey, listen, look, I know you hate these meetings.
跟前列腺检查比起来
Oh, yeah, compared to a prostate exam,
我还算喜欢的
no, I positively love them.
-我不擅长这个  戈登  -我懂
- Look, this is not my forte, Gordon. - I understand.
-姑娘们都没空  但卡梅伦说  -好
- The girls got their plates full, but Cameron says... - Okay, okay,
-博斯  你想来...  -我来搞定他们
- "Bos, you want to come in"... - Let me run them.
好吧  我懂他们的行话
Okay? I speak their language,
他们不会糊弄我  效率也更高
so they can't mess with me and it could be more efficient.
我不是想越权
Look, I'm not trying to step on your toes...
有问题再来找我
Wake me if there's a problem.
-戈登  -怎么
- Gordon. - Yeah?
谢谢你挺我
Thanks for having my back.
没什么
Yeah, sure.
听着
Listen...
我知道作为一群人里最聪明的那个是什么感受
I know what it's like to be the smartest guy in the room
我也知道试图证明这点就是浪费时间
and I also know it's a waste of time trying to prove it.
用你的工作来证明
Let your work speak for itself,
而且要知道
and be open to the possibility
那些不理解你的人
that people that don't understand you,
未必就是想妨碍你
they're not necessarily trying to get in your way.
如果没人看我的成果  要怎么证明
How can I if no one can see the work?
我有想法
I have ideas.
好想法
Real ideas.
可能听上去很理论化
They might sound theoretical,
但我可以把它变成现实
but I can make them happen.
我告诉了卡梅伦和唐娜  但她们听都不听
I told Cameron and Donna, but they didn't even listen.
她们只是让博斯给我钱让我住嘴
They just had Boz pay me to shut up.
什么想法
What ideas?
在回小屋的路上
On the way back to the lodge,
唐金斯说  我们做雪天使吧
Dawkins says, "Let's make snow angels."
他躺在雪地上  伸开双臂
He lies down in the snow, sticks out his arms,
然后醉晕了过去
and then passes out just drunk as a skunk.
在剩下的旅途中我们都叫他雪耶稣
We called him snow jesus the rest of the trip.
很高兴你滑雪滑得很开心
Okay, glad you had a good ski thing.
蒂姆说你想讨论初步计划
Tim said that you wanted to discuss first steps.
-我跟你说实话  -好
- I want to level with you. - Okay.
-你们听说AT&T砍掉视特灵了吧  -是
- I'm sure you heard about AT&T axing Viewtron. - Oh, yeah.
有些人觉得那就是网络报刊的终结
Some folks in town think that is the end of online newspapers,
但我了解
But I have got some insight
奈特里德集团内部的真正情况
into what's really going on over at Knight Ridder.
我觉得他们错失了真正的机遇
And I think that just real opportunity is being vacated there.
也就是说
Which means?
也就是说我要在可视图文上投大钱
Which means I'm gonna go in big on videotex.
我们的可用资金就会减少
It's gonna tie up more of our capital,
也就是说我无法投资140万
which also means I don't think I can do 1.4.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
那么
Oh, so...
这是拒绝了
It's a pass, then.
不  等等  这不是非黑即白的事
No, hold on. It's not that black and white.
我们还是想把你们加入到投资组合中
We still want you in the portfolio.
你们的想法有很大潜力
Your concept has just great potential.
说实话  你们两个人
And, honestly, the two of you,
真的很聪明
really sharp.
谢谢  但
Oh, thank you, but...
蒂姆  你来给她们解释一下吗
Tim, you want to walk them through it?
好  我们不能投140万
Yeah, okay, so we can't do 1.4,
但如果我们把穆特尼易物
but what if we aim for a leaner,
变得更加精简呢
meaner Mutiny Exchange?
-你是说更便宜吗  -不  更精巧
- You mean cheaper? - No, smarter.
以小做大
Doing more with less.
比如  我认为你们
Like, for instance, I think you can make do
需要雇的新员工
with half as many new hires
有计划书里的一半就够
as you have laid out in the prospectus.
对  你们可以不做服务器升级
Yeah, and I think you can skip the server computer upgrades,
至少暂时不做
at least initially.
更少风险  更多回报  行之有效
Less risk, more reward. It's a surefire way to go.
听上去不错吧
Does that sound good?
我们先停一下
You know, let's just hold off on the...
先等一下
Just for a second.
我听到的是你们想通过仅投资
What I'm hearing is that you want to lock us up
我们所需数目的一小部分来锁死我们
by investing a fraction of what we're asking.
不  你误解我们的意思了
No, you're misinterpreting what we're saying.
甲骨文也是这么来的
Oracle was the same deal.
投资会不断增加
Investment grew over time.
现在都是这样
It's how things get done out here.
好  那你们要给我们多少钱
Okay, so then how much money are you offering us?
我们还在考虑
That is a number that we are still trying to figure out.
今天的意义就在此  我们开始商谈
That's what this was all about, getting the ball rolling,
假设你们肯接受建议
assuming that you are amenable.
我们为此花了很多精力
Well, we've put a lot of thought into this
真没要求什么多余的资金
and there really isn't much fat.
其实根本就没有可减的部分
Yeah, you know, there's no fat.
在硅谷  你俩是新人
Well, ahem, you two are new to the valley
我知道你们想立马拿到你们想要的一切
and I know you want everything that you want right away.
但事实上  投资就像网球双打
But out here, funding is like doubles tennis.
你得了解你的伙伴
You got to know who you're partnering with.
你们能互相信任吗
Can you trust each other?
你们俩在一起能打好吗
Do you play well together?
合不合适呢
Is it a good fit?
这些无法通过一次会面或仅仅一顿晚餐
And that's not easy to know after just one meeting
就轻易了解
or even over dinner.
嗯  听着
Yeah, listen,
我们都知道这个行业
we both know that success
能否成功取决于时效性
in this industry comes down to timing.
我们必须第一个进入市场
We have to be first to market,
没有足够的资金
and without sufficient funding,
我们做到的可能性就大打折扣
our ability to do so is seriously compromised.
那对我们都没好处
And then we all lose.
我明白  但我们
I hear that, but let's just...
先缓缓
just take a beat,
好好吃晚餐  看看接下来会怎么样
enjoy our meal, see how the evening goes.
或许明早我会
And then maybe I will look into cutting you
给你们开张很有诚意的支票
a good-faith check in the morning.
我出去打个电话
I'm gonna pop out for a call.
你们考虑考虑
Just think it over.
我以为这是严肃的会面
I thought this was a serious meeting.
我们很严肃
We are serious.
刚才那是怎么回事
What the hell was that?
那是个机会
It was an opportunity
能让你们脱颖而出
for you guys to jump to the front of the line.
那难道不是你们想要的吗
Isn't that what you wanted?
如果他有什么误会的话  我道歉
Wow, okay, my apologies if he misread things.
怎么可能误会
What could he have possibly misread?
我们一直表现得很专业
We have been nothing but professional.
你开玩笑吧  两周来你们每天都打电话
Are you kidding? You guys call every day for two weeks.
他一打给你们  你们就放下一切来赴宴
You drop everything the night he calls you to dinner.
抱歉  但涂了那种颜色的口红
And I'm sorry, but nobody wears that shade of lipstick
就该是玩得起的
unless they have come to play.
我们要走了
We're going.
不行  我要告诉他...
No, you know what? I'm going to tell him...
我们的光盘不能只出现在
I want our discs available beyond stores
计算机商店里
aimed at the computer crowd.
如果大家找不到  免费又有何意义
What's the point of making something free if no one can find it?
别那么死板
Listen, be creative.
我们的目标是刚使用计算机的用户
We're after first-time PC users.
我们应该出现在杂货店  音像店  商场
We should be in grocery stores, video stores, malls.
我们要无处不在
We want to be everywhere they are.
我希望人们看腻了我们
I want people sick of seeing us
就像我不想再见到你们一样  去吧
the same way I'm sick of seeing you. Go.
辛西娅
Cynthia!
-你是莱恩·雷吗  -是的
- Are you Ryan Ray? - Yeah.
麦克米伦先生要见你
Mr. MacMillan will see you.
这一周每天上午9点
Every day this week at 9:00 a.m.,
我都有与莱恩·雷见面的安排
I've got a meeting scheduled with Ryan Ray.
你做这个花了多长时间
How long did this take you?
两个小时
Two hours.
好  你见到我了
Okay, you're here.
为了见我一面你花了不少功夫
You've gone to a lot of trouble to be here.
我给你三分钟时间
You've got three minutes.
那我就开门见山了
Okay, then I'll cut to the chase.
我想在麦克米伦实用网络工作
I want to work at MacMillan utility.
"我想"和"我得"有很大区别
Want is very different than need.
好吧  我得在这里工作
Okay, I need to work here.
为什么
Why?
因为我对杀毒软件很感兴趣
Because I'm fascinated by antivirus software.
我没兴趣  我觉得无聊
I'm not. It bores me.
好吧  因为你设立了标杆
Okay, um, because you set the gold standard
还在寻找下一个挑战
and you're looking for your next challenge.
我也一样
I am, too.
你凭什么认为自己知道我想要什么
What makes you think you know what I'm looking for?
我不知道
I don't.
是啊  那太冒昧了  只有你自己才知道
Yeah, that was presumptuous. Only you know that.
你凭什么认为我知道自己想要什么呢
What makes you think I know what I'm looking for?
因为你很厉害  等等  你不知道吗
Because you're brilliant. Wait, don't you?
你不必回答这个问题
I mean, you don't have to answer that.
你凭什么要回答呢  我不过是...
Why would you? I just...
无论你下一步做什么  我都要加入
Whatever you want to do next, I'm in.
这是一场测试  我给出了错误答案  是吗
This is a test and that was the wrong answer, right?
这是一场测试  我给出了正确答案
This is a test and that was the right answer?
我不知道你想让我说什么
I don't know what you want me to say.
你来到这里真正想说的
Whatever you actually came here to say.
我觉得我还没听到呢
I can't imagine that I've heard it yet.
我觉得你不喜欢我  我说什么都不要紧
I feel like you're judging me. It doesn't matter what I say.
即使你不说话  也看上去很失望
Even when you're not talking, you seem disappointed.
你可以问我天空是什么颜色
You could ask me what color the sky is
即使我说蓝色也会是错的
and I would say blue and somehow I'd be wrong.
确实  现在是阴天
You would be. It's overcast.
是你提携了默默无名的戈登·克拉克
You plucked Gordon Clark out of obscurity, right?
在他遇见你之前  什么都不是
He was nothing before he met you.
我认识他  我跟他一起工作
I know him. I work with him.
你老这么说
So you keep saying.
我跟他一样好
I'm just as good as he is
而且更努力  主动
and a hard worker with initiative.
我知道你冲浪  所以我连续两周
I learned you surfed, so I woke up at 5:00 in the morning
每天凌晨5点起床  找了11片海滩才找到你
for two weeks straight and cased 11 beaches to find you.
我黑了一家安全公司
I hacked a security company.
你的安全公司
Your security company.
这难道不能证明...
Doesn't any of that prove that...
好吧  这听起来可能会很奇怪
Okay, this is gonna sound weird,
我自己说出来也觉得很可笑
and I feel ridiculous even saying this,
但我知道有事要发生
but I know that something's coming.
大事
Something big.
像是一列火车  而我只想跳上去
Like a train and all I want is to jump on board.
但它开得越来越快
But it's getting faster and faster
我害怕自己会错过它
and I'm terrified that I'm gonna miss it.
你在卡斯特罗剧院演讲的那晚
That night... that night that you spoke at the Castro,
我就觉得  终于
I was like, finally,
有人和我的想法一样
somebody sees the world the way I do.
那时我就知道  这就是我的火车票
And I knew right then that this was my ticket on that train.
我不知道还能告诉你什么
I don't know what else to tell you, man.
我只想和你共事...我必须得和你共事
I just want to work with you... need to work with you.
做什么都好
On anything.
求求你了
Please.
没人听我的话
Nobody listens to me.
没人认真对待我
No one takes me seriously.
我不想被落下
I don't want to get left behind.
你的三分钟到了
Your three minutes are up.
你看起来很好
You look great.
克拉克女士  豪伊小姐
Mrs. Clark, Miss Howe.
请跟我来
Follow me.
谢谢
Thank you.
这边走
We're just going right down there.
谢谢
Thank you.
-好了  -该坐吗
- Okay. - Should we sit?
你们好
Hello.
-黛安  -唐娜
- Oh, Diane. - Donna, hi.
天啊  我好笨
Oh, my god, I feel so stupid.
我没想到你就是阿马多·古德·吉尔森的合伙人
I had no idea you were the Gould in Amador Gould Gilson.
世界真小  这里更小
Small world. Smaller valley.
太好了  我们不用浪费时间
But this is great. Now we don't have to waste time
寒暄闲聊了
exchanging pleasantries or small talk.
这位是...
Except for...
卡梅伦·豪伊
Yes, Cameron Howe.
黛安是琼妮同学的妈妈
Oh, Diane is a mom at Joanie's school.
好的
Okay.
等等  是被琼妮打了的那个女孩的妈妈吗
Oh, wait, the mom of the girl that Joanie beat up?
我听说是个平手
I heard it was more of a draw.
这位是伊莱亚斯·阿马多  他也来听听
This is Elias Amador. He'll be joining us.
你好
Hello.
说实话  我还没来得及看计划书
Full disclosure, I haven't had time to read this,
但我欣赏穆特尼的发展
but love how you've grown Mutiny
非常期待你们的推介
and can't wait to hear what you've got.
这真是美好的意外之喜
I can't tell you what a nice change this is,
能见到熟人  还有伊莱亚斯
pitching to a familiar face and Elias.
-我们可以...  -准备好就可以开始了
- Shall we just...? - Whenever you're ready.
请想象一个地方
Imagine a place you could go
你所有热爱  收集和为之疯狂的东西
where whatever your passion, whatever you collect or love,
只需一键就能找到
it's available to you at the push of a button.
稀有的《蜘蛛侠》漫画  盗版的狄伦演唱会
A rare spider-man comic, a bootleg Dylan concert,
菲茨杰拉德初版小说
First edition Fitzgerald,
甚至是难找的苹果二号零件
even a hard-to-find part for your Apple II.
应有尽有  无需走遍当地跳蚤市场
It's all there. You don't have to scour the local flea market.
期望那里可能有你所需
On the chance that they might have it.
或是转遍车库甩卖
Or hit every garage sale.
期望那里可能有你所需
On the chance that they might have it.
你甚至不用出门
Or even leave your home.
因为你与全国人民连接在了一起
Because you're connecting to people across the country
-他们都是...  -请容我打断你们一下
- who are all part of... - Let me stop you right there.
你们说的这一切听起来很棒
Everything you're saying sounds terrific,
但我就直说了
but just to cut to the chase,
你们是准备将核心业务从聊天转变成交易吗
you're shifting your core business from chat to trade, yes?
不是转变  是扩张
No, not shifting. We're expanding.
这不是第一次了  我们以游戏起家
And it isn't the first time. We started with games.
然后发现玩家会在游戏中聊天
We noticed that our users were chatting during games,
于是我们开始做聊天室  我们的用户群指数增长
so we moved into chat and our base jumped exponentially.
然后我们发现我们的用户在聊天期间做交易
And then we noticed that our users were trading during chat,
我们是依据用户行为开拓市场的
so we go where the user behavior takes us.
这是我们经营模式  事实证明是非常高效的
It's our business model and it's proven to be highly effective.
嗯  我要问清楚
Right, just to be clear, though,
你们的扩张是基于
your expansion is predicated
在论坛上交换物品的点子
on the idea of swapping goods through a BBS?
-是的  -没错
- Yes. - Yes, exactly.
伊莱亚斯  想问什么吗
Elias, anything you'd like to ask?
不用  谢谢
I'm good. Thank you.
好了  多谢你们前来
Okay, thank you for coming in.
很荣幸  我们很期待...
Our pleasure. We'll look forward to...
恐怕我们得拒绝了
But I'm afraid it's a pass.
抱歉...我不懂
I'm sor... I don't understand.
你们不至少看看我们的数据吗
Don't you want to at least look at the numbers?
不了  抱歉
No, sorry.
好吧  多谢你们抽时间
Okay, well, thank you for your time.
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢谢你们前来  -嗯
- Thank you for coming in. - Yeah.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
还女性自强呢
So much for sisters doing it for themselves.
天呐  人说仅次于同意的就是干净利落的拒绝了
Jesus, they say the next best thing to a yes is a quick no.
这也太利落了
You can't get much quicker than that.
是啊  回绝得也太快了
Yeah, well, that was too goddamn quick.
就好像她看到是我时就已经决定了
It's like she made up her mind when she saw it was me.
不  不是的
No, she didn't.
克拉克先生  是你编写了黑掉了
Mr. Clark, you created the Sonaris virus
西方网络的索纳里斯病毒  是吗
that took down WestNet, yes?
不  我写了一个测绘网络大小的获取程序
No, I created a fetch program to detect network size.
但由于编码失误  它开始自我扩散
Due to an error, it self-propagated.
我跟病毒感染西方网络完全无关
I had nothing to do with it infecting WestNet.
但你的争议点在于麦克米伦杀毒软件
But it's your contention that the MacMillan antivirus software
是这个获取程序的变体
is a variation of this fetch program?
不  不是变体
No, no, it's not a variation.
452千行代码里只改了两千行
Only two kilo lines of code out of 452 were changed.
我之所以知道  因为那是我改的
I know this because I changed them myself
然后亲手拿去给了乔
and hand-delivered it to Joe.
是啊  他之后可能加了点花里胡哨的东西
Yes, he may have added some bells and whistles since then,
但是  他别想糊弄谁
but, come on, he's not fooling anyone.
你说你亲手拿去给了他
When you say you hand-delivered the program,
那是作为礼物  还是交易
was that a gift or a transaction?
礼物不也是一种交易吗
Aren't gifts a type of transaction?
礼物是给朋友的
You give a gift to a friend.
交易是跟生意伙伴完成的
You have a transaction with a business partner.
这是你现编的吗  还是真有这么个说法
Okay, did you just make that up or is that a real thing?
克拉克先生  你1985年7月30日
Mr. Clark, at what address did you live
当时的住址是哪里
on the date of July 30, 1985?
跟我1985年2月17日
Same address that I lived at on February 17, 1985,
1985年1月27日和1985年5月1日
and January 27, 1985, and May 1, 1985,
和其他你问到的日期的住址是一样的
and every other date that you've asked me about.
能请你重复下那个地址吗
Could you please repeat the address?
德克萨斯州  理查德森  蒂普街2824号
2824 Depue Drive, Richardson, Texas.
麦克米伦先生是否
And did Mr. MacMillan visit you
曾于1985年7月30日去过
at your residence at 2824 Depue Drive
你蒂普街2824号的房子
on July 30, 1985?
是的
Yes.
他怎么知道你住在那里的
And how did he know that you lived at said address?
因为他去过
Because he had been there before.
他为什么会去过
And why had he been there before?
因为我们曾是合作伙伴
Because we were business partners.
还是朋友
And friends?
是啊  朋友
Yeah, and friends.
他1985年7月30日
So, when he visited you on July 30, 1985,
去蒂普街2824号拜访你时
at 2824 Depue Drive,
是作为生意伙伴  还是朋友
was that as a business partner or a friend?
我不知道
I don't know.
你得去问他
You'd have to ask him.
你看呢
From your perspective.
我看
From my perspective?
我看  乔·麦克米伦做事只有一个原因
From my perspective, Joe MacMillan does things for one reason
没有其他
and one reason only and th...
拜托  我们在...
Hey, excuse me, we are right...
我们说好的
We had an agreement
取证要分别私下进行  麦克米伦先生
to keep these depositions private, Mr. MacMillan.
请继续说完
Please, finish that thought.
因为他是个自私  自厌
Because he's a selfish, self-loathing,
自利的混蛋
self-serving piece of shit.
我愿给你50%我在公司的股份
I'm prepared to offer you 50% of my stake in the company.
麦克米伦先生  这...
Mr. MacMillan, this is completely...
均分  但有一个条件
It's an even split. I've got one condition.
我要你来跟我一起经营
I want you to come run it with me.
麦克米伦先生  这种事
Mr. MacMillan, I'd really
你最好提前跟我...
prefer that you run something like this...
亚伦  没事的
Aaron, it's fine.
60%
60%.
70%
70%.
来做我的合伙人
Come be my partner
你就能拥有70%的公司股份
and 70% of the company is yours.
克拉克先生  以我专业之见
Mr. Clark, my professional advice
最好认真考虑...
would be to seriously consider...
我想声明
I'd like to state for the
这并非正式提议
record that this is not a legitimate offer.
非常正式  你给我什么我都签
It's fully legitimate. I'll sign anything you put in front of me.
只要你一句话  戈登
Just say the word, Gordon.
我不想跟你合作  乔
I don't want to work with you, Joe.
现在我们知道这宗诉讼究竟是为了什么了
I think we now know what this lawsuit is really about.
回到1985年7月30日
Returning to the date of July 30, 1985,
克拉克先生  依你看
Mr. Clark, from your perspective,
乔·麦克米伦前往你位于
did Joe MacMillan come to your residence
蒂普街2824号的房子时
at 2824 Depue Drive
是作为生意伙伴  还是朋友
as a business partner or a friend?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我们究竟要找什么
What are we looking for anyway?
错误
A mistake.
我父母在卧室里
My parents are up in their bedroom
为我的生日派对包礼物
wrapping presents for my birthday party.
好像我不知道他们在做什么似的
Like I don't know exactly what they're doing.
他们还当我是小孩
They still think of me as little.
那是因为他们没像我那样
Well, it's 'cause they've never seen you
见过你喝威士忌  抽雪茄
throw back a whiskey and smoke a cigar like I have.
我才没那么做呢
I never did that!
你在开玩笑
You're joking.
真希望我不用开生日派对
I wish I didn't have to have a birthday party.
我觉得生日派对没意思
I don't believe in birthday parties.
这也行吗
You can do that?
当然  你的生日  你想做什么都行
Yeah, it's your birthday. You can do whatever you want.
你找到错误了吗
Did you find the mistake?
没有
No.
你父母逼你开的
So who's coming to this stupid party
你又不想开的破派对
your parents are making you throw
都会有谁来
that you don't really want to have anyway?
我们出去吧  好吗
Okay, let's take it outside, okay?
好了  各位
All right, everybody,
我们去后院吧
let's move it on out to the backyard.
出去吧  我们走
Slip'n slide is out there. Let's go, let's go.
都出去  快走
Everybody out. Move it.
快走  出去
Get out of here. Go. Go.
琼妮  又有客人来了
Joanie, you've got another guest to greet.
琼妮
Joanie!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
请进
Come on in.
詹妮弗知道是哪条街
Jennifer knew the name of the street,
但不知道具体地址
but not the address.
所以我们停好车  祈祷  然后循着尖叫声来了
So we parked, prayed, and followed the screams.
没想到你会来
I wasn't expecting you.
琼妮请了詹妮弗
Joanie invited Jennifer
我又是她的司机
and seeing as how I am her chauffeur,
所以就一起来了  这个该放哪
we're part of a package deal. Where should I put this?
其他姑娘和礼物桌都在后面
You know what? The girls and the gift table are all out back.
她居然来了
I cannot believe she's here.
看来琼妮和詹妮弗和好了
I guess Joanie patched things up with Jennifer.
天呐  这年纪的女孩  真是疯了
God, I'm telling you, girls at this age, it's crazy.
前一天还是死敌
One day they're mortal enemies,
第二天就成闺蜜了
the next day they're best friends.
怎么了
What?
她都来了
Well, I mean, she's here.
我们不该利用一下吗
Should we take advantage of it?
不  我才不想再被羞辱
No, I don't want to face that humiliation again.
爸爸  看我啊
Daddy, daddy! Watch me!
莱恩  你来了
Hey, Ryan, you made it.
是啊  我不能待太久
Yeah. I can't stay long.
-当然  派对很棒的  -谢谢
- Not that it's not a nice party. - Thanks.
不过我也不了解
I wouldn't know;
我没参加过10岁女孩的生日派对
I've never been to a 10-year-old's birthday party.
10岁之后就没有过了
Well, not since I was 10.
大人在这种场合里该做什么
What do grown-ups do at these things?
喝酒
Oh, well, drink.
那个
Hey, so...
听着  我们今天不该谈工作上的事
So listen, we're not supposed to be talking shop today,
但我知道该怎么推进你关于聊天室的点子
but I had a few ideas on how to move your chat idea forward.
是吗  怎么做
Oh, yeah? Really? How?
嗯  听着
Yeah, well, all right, listen.
几年前  计算机服务的民用电台模拟器
A few years back, CompuServe had this CB simulator
让我超级着迷
that I was totally obsessed with.
我们可以把那个作为基本模板
We could start with that as a rudimentary template.
我的点子比计算机服务先进多了
My idea is way more advanced than CompuServe.
我知道  我们只需要他们的
I know, I know. All we would take from CompuServe is...
模拟器的共享内存虚拟阵列管理器代码
is the shared memory virtual array manager from the CBsim code.
我们可以扩展它  以支持更多用户
We make it bigger so we can support more users
其他的我们就从零建起
and the rest we build from scratch.
这是能节省时间
That would be a time-saver.
是啊
Yeah, totally.
过来
Come here.
没人是在真空中做设计
No one designs in a vacuum.
如果你真正的创新点在于轮胎
What's the point in reinventing the wheel
何必重新发明轮子呢
if your true innovation is creating the tire?
是啊
Yeah.
比如巨人电脑
Take the Giant, okay?
随你怎么损它  但我是从IBM个人电脑做起
Say what you will about it, but I started with a IBM PC
最终产品比它快一倍  便宜一半
and made something that was twice as fast at half the cost
而且仅重15磅  十分便携
and portable at 15 pounds.
那不是乔·麦克米伦做的吗
I thought that was Joe MacMillan.
乔·麦克米伦或许空想出了一堆参数
Joe MacMillan might have pulled the specs out of his ass,
但把空想变成现实
but turning them into a working product?
那可不是他的长项
No, not really his bag of tricks.
你好啊  莱恩  看
Howdy, Ryan. Look at this.
-什么啊  -给琼妮买的
- What you got there? - Got it for Joanie.
-机器人管家  -太可笑了
- Robo butler. - That looks ridiculous.
反正又不是你过生日  是吧
Yeah, well, it ain't your birthday, is it?
-究竟做什么的  -来  看看
- What's it do exactly? - Here, look at this.
看啊
Lookit here.
过来  我展示给你看
Come here, let me show you. Come on.
好了  来
Look, all right, here.
把你的啤酒放进它的小金属爪子里
Get your beers right there into the metal paws. Come on.
如果还得把酒放进它手里
If you got to put the beers in his hands,
何不直接自己拿着好了
why don't you just take them with you?
让机器人拿给你有什么意义啊
I mean, what's the point of having the robot bring them to you?
因为他是管家  这是他的工作
'cause he's a butler, man. It's what he does.
-好吧  -退后  看着
- All right. - Now back up. Back up. Watch.
琼妮肯定会喜欢的
Joanie gonna love this.
看啊  去吧  管家
Look at him. Come on there, butler.
瞧我啊  我是个机器人管家
Look at me, I'm robo butler.
先生们想再来点酒吗
Would you gentlemen care for more beers?
博斯  它好慢啊
Bos, it's so slow.
它走得那么慢
I mean, look, it's taking forever to get here.
我自己过去都快点
I could've walked over here faster.
我还有收据
I got the receipt.
别把这个给琼妮
Don't give that to Joanie,
她只会不开心的
All right. You're only gonna upset her.
她会喜欢的
She gonna love it.
很高兴琼妮和詹妮弗的关系好起来了
Hey, nice to see Joanie and Jennifer getting along.
我要告诉你  我一周能听60个推介
Just so you know, I get 60 proposals a week.
大部分时候  我会全部拒绝
Most weeks I pass on all 60.
并不是针对你
It really had nothing to do with you.
我完全理解
No, I completely understand.
只是你拒绝得好快
It was a really quick no you gave us in there, though.
好吧  我们谈吧  但去别的地方
All right, let's talk, but not out here.
你们在笑我的管家吗  孩子
Are you laughing at my butler, children?
走开  都走开
Get out of here. Scram, all of you.
快走  该死的管家
Get out of here. Dang butler.
真是的  老天爷啊
Oh, hell. Oh, for christ's sake.
我一直在梳理我们的计划书
I've been combing over our prospectus,
回想我们的会面
replaying our meeting,
想搞明白伊莱亚斯的纸条为什么搞砸了一切
trying to figure out why Elias's note derailed things.
我已经锁定在三种可能性之间了
I've narrowed it down to three possibilities.
一  伊莱亚斯不认为我们的用户群
A, Elias doesn't believe our user base
能像我们预期的那样接受穆特尼易物
will embrace Mutiny Exchange as rapidly as our projections,
这是错的
which is wrong.
二  伊莱亚斯认为我们对开发到测试的时间表
B, Elias thinks our timeframe from development to beta
过于乐观了  这也是错的
is overly optimistic, which is also wrong.
三  伊莱亚斯是个性别歧视的混蛋
C, Elias is a sexist jerk
他不认为两个女人能经营好公司
who doesn't believe two women can run a company, which...
-好了  -我比较倾向于第三种
- Okay. - I'm leaning towards c.
伊莱亚斯的确是个性别歧视的混蛋
Elias is a sexist jerk,
但比大部分人强
but better than most.
他才不在乎谁经营一家公司
He doesn't care who runs a company
只要能挣钱就行
as long as it makes him money.
好吧  那我不明白了  因为你是个聪明人
Okay, then I'm at a loss because you're a smart woman
易物是个好主意
and Exchange is a great idea.
我是聪明  这点子也的确很棒
I am smart and it is a great idea.
这就是你们的问题所在  你们没想到第四点
And that's your problem. You didn't allow for D.
已经有别家公司在做这个了
Another company is already doing this.
什么  谁
What? Who?
一家小公司
It's a small outfit
伊莱亚斯在考察他们的投资可能
Elias has been tracking as a potential investment.
跳蚤市场
Swapmeet.
好名字
It's a good name.
我之前不知道
I wasn't aware of it.
否则就不会让你们来了
Otherwise I never would have had you come in.
你对他们有什么了解
What do you know about them?
只知道他们已经做了18个月了
Only that they have an 18-month head start.
而且说到底
And at the end of the day,
这是我们决定的依据
that's what informed our decision.
我们没道理下注在穆特尼身上
It made no sense to bet on Mutiny
这场仗你们不仅是要输
in a battle you weren't just losing,
甚至不知道自己在打
but didn't even know you were fighting.
等等  伙计们  想来玩吗
Hey, wait, guys, do you want to come play?
我们玩个游戏吧
Okay, let's play a game.
亲爱的  你还好吗
Hey, sweetie. You doing okay?
她把注意力都吸引走了  是吧
Oh, she's really pulling focus, isn't she?
就好像是她的生日派对  而不是你的
Kind of like it's her birthday party and not yours.
亲爱的  我只想告诉你
Look, honey, I just want you to know
我是多么为你骄傲
how proud I am of you
因为你邀请了詹妮弗
For inviting Jennifer.
这很成熟
It shows real maturity.
-好吧  -生日不仅仅是一场派对
- Okay. - A birthday's not just a party.
而是标志了你人生的历程
It's marking a passage of time in your life.
你让我看到  你不再是个小女孩了
You're showing me you're not just a little girl anymore...
我知道啦  我长大了  你为我自豪
Okay, I heard you. Growing up and you're proud of me.
我们能切蛋糕了吗
Can we just do the cake now?
不  过来
No, no. Come here.
我希望你真的明白我的话
I want to make sure you hear what I'm saying.
你今天的做法很成熟
Okay, you did a really grown-up thing today
爸爸
and your dad,
此时此刻非常为你骄傲
he couldn't be more proud of you than he is right now.
别再那么说了
Stop saying that.
卡梅伦付了我20美元让我请詹妮弗来的
Cameron paid me 20 bucks to invite Jennifer to come.
好吗
Okay?
我讨厌詹妮弗
I hate Jennifer.
我们能切蛋糕了吗
Can we just do the cake now, please?
-大家都在问  -好
- Everyone's asking for it. - Yeah, sure.
我们去切蛋糕吧
Let's do the cake.
我在穆特尼上到处打听了
Okay, I've been on Mutiny asking around,
想问问关于这个跳蚤市场的信息
trying to figure out what I could about this Swapmeet.
-怎么样  -就我看来
- And? - From what I can tell,
它的构想
it sounds seriously less robust
远不如我们对易物的构想宏大
than what we have in mind for Exchange.
而且  它主攻体育纪念品
Plus, it's focused on sports memorabilia,
我觉得它根本赶不上
so I just can't see it reaching anywhere
我们的用户群大
near the size and scope of our user base.
詹妮弗居然
Hey, sure was weird
会来参加派对  真是奇怪  是吧
that Jennifer came to the party, wasn't it?
是啊  我们不能输给不如我们的东西
Yeah. We will not lose to an inferior product.
我不要被这种东西比下去
I refuse to be Betamax.
我好像没请她来
'cause I don't remember inviting her.
不是我们  是琼妮自己决定的
Oh, no, we didn't. Joanie did that all on her own.
多成熟啊
Wasn't that mature of her?
是啊
Yeah, it was.
她能邀请詹妮弗
It shows a hell of a lot of maturity
真是太成熟了
that she would invite Jennifer.
倒是提醒我了
Which, you know, reminds me.
干什么  这是干吗的
What? What is this for?
感谢你今天的帮忙
For all your help today.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
我回屋了
I'll be in my room.
她去替派对买杯子来着
She went out and grabbed some cups for us at the party.
莱恩·雷
Ryan Ray.
莱恩
Ryan.
麦克米伦先生
Mr. MacMillan.
莱恩  帮我个忙
Ryan, I want you to do something for me.
好的
Okay.
干什么
What?
我要你站起来
I want you to stand up.
我要你好好看看周围
I want you to take a long look around.
你一定要把
I want you to make sure you see
房间里的每个人都收进眼底
every single person in that room.
-你在做了吗  -是的
- Are you doing that? - Yeah.
很好
Good.
忘记他们吧
Now forget them,
他们不再是你的同事了
because you don't work with those people anymore.
明早9点整  我办公室见
I'll see you tomorrow at my office, 9:00 a.m. sharp.
天呐
Oh, my god.
我会到的
I'll be there.
谢谢
Thank you.
莱恩  还有件事
Now, Ryan, there's one more thing
我需要你做
I want you to do for me.
-难以置信  -看
- Incredible. - Look.
她来了  转过来
It's her. Turn around.
有点正式了吧
Isn't this a bit formal for us?
我们可以
We could just meet
下个月在詹妮弗的生日派对上见
at Jennifer's birthday party next month.
不  我们就好
Oh, no, we'll just be a minute.
我真的很欣赏坚持
I admire persistence, I really do,
但我们都说过了
but we've been over this.
就算我想
Even if I wanted to,
我也不能说服我的合伙人资助你们扩张
I couldn't convince my partners to fund your expansion.
-对不起  -不  我们理解
- I'm sorry. - No, we understand.
-我们不是为此而来  -你是对的
- That's not why we're here. - No, because you're right.
跳蚤市场是我们的竞争对手
Swapmeet is our competition.
你们投资一百多万  看我们追进度
It'd be foolish for you to invest over a million dollars
太傻了
just to see if we can catch up.
所以我们做足了功课
And that's why we've done our homework.
我们发现
And what we found is that
跳蚤市场虽然有可行的程序
while swapmeet does have a functional program
而这我们需要追赶一年甚至更久
that it would take us a year or more to compete with,
但他们比不上的
what they don't have
是我们广大的用户群
is anywhere near the size of our user base.
我们不要求你帮我们跟跳蚤市场竞争
We don't want you to help us compete with swapmeet.
我们希望你帮我们买下他们
We want you to help us buy them.
打一场仗不需要一百万
It's not a million to fight a war,
赢下战争只需要几十万
it's a few hundred thousand to win it.
太好了
Yes!
天呐  真抱歉
Oh, my god, I'm... I'm so sorry.
莱恩  好消息
Hey, Ryan. Great news.
我找到了民用电台模拟器的代码
I tracked down that CBsim code,
我们今天就可以开始了
so we can get started today.
就你和我
You know, just... just you and me.
我要去为乔·麦克米伦工作了
I'm going to work for Joe MacMillan.